Ajinkya Deshmukh

USA

26123 Bouquet Canyon Rd. Unit 108 Santa Clarita, CA, 91350 +1(315)-560-8787 INDIA 137/20 Vidya Vilas Colony Aundh, Pune, 411007

EMAIL: ajinkyardeshmukh@yahoo.com

Summary

I have been working as a Software Developer for the past 5 years. I develop software applications that provide Web based solutions to businesses. Most of the projects utilize agile-like development processes using JIRA etc. My day to day includes collaborating with the UX team, resolving front-end bugs and tickets, configuring unit tests/ test libraries and integrating end points. I have a diverse job history which includes sailing on cargo ships, interning as a systems analyst in sales and being a software consultant to large multinational corporations

Skills

- React, Angular, Javascript, Typescript
- CSS,SASS, Bootstrap, Carbon Design, Material Design
- HTML, XHTML, XPages, JSF, AJAX, JSON
- Node JS, Go, Docker, Kubernetes
- MongoDB, DB2, MySQL, DominoDB

Experience

IBM, San Francisco - Software Developer

Sept 2020 - PRESENT

Application name: Q2C

- Working in a team developing a global IBM application for their sales team.
- Developing the app in the latest version of React with Go as the backend language and the use of containerization with Docker and Kubernetes
- Implementing the Carbon components framework for React to maintain UI consistency
- Integrating and updating legacy React code with React Hooks
- Implementing styled components wherever possible and using common functions and components and working with the team to integrate typescript wherever possible
- Recently started documentation of Orientation, VS Code extensions and functions to allow future new hires better visibility for the application

Princess Cruises, Santa Clarita - Software Developer

June 2017 - July 2020

Application name: OnDeck and Trip Assist Portal

- Developed a global travel disruption and incident management application for Princess Cruises and its parent company Carnival Corp.
- Involved in multiple functionality and speed improvements of the application in a distributed network with limited connectivity.
- Leveraged the use of IndexDb, Local and session storage for the application to improve speed
- Helped the application transition from legacy XHTML and Notes DB backend to use the MEAN stack, followed by Angular 4 then the final version with React
- Implemented the Material Design concept for the application using Angular Material
- Helped develop apis that allow for bulk booking of flights and hotels for guests in the case of emergencies and incidents all over the world
- Developed a guest facing webapp for mobile users on board the ship using React and WCAG/ADA compliance design principles.
- Implemented excel reporting using Apache POI
- Developed apis and a small webapp for internal users to request data to be pushed from the servers to the systems
- Improved the CSS and UI of the application working with the UX designer
- The application was used extensively during the start of the pandemic and during the times when guests were allowed to return to their home countries
- The application allowed users to book ~ 10k flight tickets in under an hour
- Worked with microsoft sharepoint, azure and PowerApps to implement small apps for the team to use for logs and excel reporting

IBM, San Francisco / Austin - Software Developer

Sept 2016 - May 2017

Application name: GSS and GUDA

- Worked on two projects while at IBM
- #1 Developed a scheduler app (GSS) that would help managers assign tasks and work orders to field technicians and other onsite workers
- Application UI was developed using Javascript, JSF and Fullcalender.js
- Application backend used Java and consumed JSON data
- Front end UI used bootstrap to allow the use of the calendar on mobile devices for field engineers
- Worked on the second stage of the application which would move to a Node JS, Angular JS, and MongoDB stack.

- Leveraged DBeaver and eclipse to maintain data in the DB.
- Performed in depth testing of application functionality to remove bugs and defects before launch.
- Added additional functionality to UI based on user experience reports.
- Helped launch the application in multiple US based IBM territories.
- #2 Developed an app (GUDA that monitored, documented, granted permissions and updated managerial changes within IBM
- AngularJS and JavaScript were used to design functionality and HTML5, Bootstrap and CSS for UI.
- Performed usability testing of the mobile and web application. Designed and recommended changes as necessary. Worked on defects before and after application launch.
- Cross Browser Functionality Testing
- Worked with the user experience team to come with best possible UI design for the end users.
- Used CSS3 features like gradients, rounded corners, Drop shadows with graceful degradation for non-supportive browsers.

YP, San Francisco - Software Developer

Dec 2015 - July 2016

Application name: YP4B Web

- Developed a Customer portal for business to manage their yellow pages profiles and track metrics
- Worked in proximity with Juhll, Optimizely, Sales Tool and Salesforce teams to provide the metrics for the customers
- Learned the use of Postman, Splunk and other technologies
- Application was built in the MEAN stack.
- Supported an application and was involved in converting the legacy .NET code to the MEAN stack

Internships

May 2014 - Sept 2014

Cisco, Boston - Systems Engineer

- Interned with Cisco as a systems engineering intern working mainly for the sales team
- Developed a better understanding of the business side of software technology and how it is marketed as a product
- Conducted in-depth financial, competitive, strategic and industry analyses for commercial and enterprise accounts in healthcare, insurance, manufacturing and technology

Apr 2012 - Dec 2012

Teekay Marine Ltd - *7unior Engineer*

- Sailed aboard an aframax oil tanker for 7 months as junior engineer
- In charge of data log management and waste management systems on the ship

• Developed a better understanding of the control systems onboard the ship to allow for automation and the combination between the software and mechanical components of the ship

Education

Aug 2013 - May 2015

Syracuse University, New York - Energy Systems Engineering

July 2008 - Jan 2013

BITS, Pilani (Tolani Maritime Institute) - Marine Engineering